Ioan Bodiu (John)

5 Castle field Park, Clonsilla, Dublin

M: 087 7217823 E: johnbodiu@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

Over 5 year's IT support experience and degrees in Mechanical Engineering and Manufacturing & Design. Key strengths include attention to detail, achieving challenging goals, hard-working person, self-motivated and can work under pressure towards deadlines. I can maintain excellent working relationships with colleagues and customers alike. Dedicated to improve and excel in the roles offered as a professional.

KEY SKILLS / ATTRIBUTES

- Advanced IT / Technology skills
- MS Office
- Full Irish driving licence
- Project Management
- Native English speaker

EDUCATION

2018-2020: BEng Manufacturing and Design Engineering (Hons)

Technological University Dublin (Formerly DIT)

Thesis: Manufacturing processes and Mould Design of an innovative phone case.

2015-2018: BEngTech Mechanical Engineering (Ord)

Technological University Dublin (Formerly DIT).

Thesis: Automatic garden clothesline rain protection system.

2010-2015: Leaving Certificate & Junior Certificate

Blakestown Community School, Blanchardstown.

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2023-Current: IT Specialist - Applegreen

- Install and configure appropriate software and functions according to corporate specifications
- Ensure security and privacy of networks and computer systems
- Provide orientation and guidance to users on how to operate new software and computer equipment
- Organize and schedule upgrades and maintenance
- Perform troubleshooting to diagnose and resolve problems (repair or replace parts, debugging etc.)
- Maintain records/logs of repairs and fixes and maintenance schedule
- Configuration and maintenance of all hardware and software throughout the company at different locations.
- Assist with the prompt resolution of support service tickets
- Using a wide range of tools such as Active Directory, SCCM, 0365 suite, Admin centres, Service Now
- Knowledge of Network and Storage solutions Routers, Servers, Firewalls etc

Winter 2020: Field Service Engineer – Store Cmputer Technology

Working as a project engineer to install or repair technological equipment in a variety of customer sites. For example installing new hardware for the multinational supermarket chain – Lidl GmbH

June 2017-June 2023: IT analyst - Store Computer Technology

As part of a team, I acted as a point of contact for IT related incidents for retail customers and responsible for arranging engineer visits when required.

Acting as Level 2 support, I troubleshooted IT incidents using remote desktop connection or phone calls from all areas of retail business within agreed parameters

2013-2017: Labourer - Construction Industry

Part-time work while in Secondary school and first two years of College.

Duties included: Loading and unloading building materials and moving materials towards working areas. Operated a range of equipment and machinery. Cleaned tools, equipment and work area

INTERESTS

Sport: Soccer, Basketball, Karting, Ping Pong, Other

Travel: Germany, UAE, Spain, Belgium, France, Austria, UK, etc

Other: Book reading, Youth activities volunteer, Street charity volunteer

REFEREES

Mr Gerry Woods Programme Chair, BEng Manufacturing and Design Engineering

Technological University Dublin, Bolton Street, Dublin 1

Mr John Hogan Managing Director, Store Computer Technology

Mr Carmine Service Manager, Applegreen

Mr Macedon Builder Expert, Plastering Services

References given on request